THAMSANOA EMMANUEL SANHEWE

- @ ethamsanqa@gmail.com
- 078 990 8279 / 081 887 9796





Objective

I am a highly focused ambitious and dedicated individual, having experience in site supervision, records management, Information technology and financial management. I believe that my leadership skills, communication skills, ability to network and be receptive to input from colleagues and capabilities gained through my qualifications and experience make me a strong candidate and valuable asset.



Experience

Department Of Home Affairs (Head Office, Pretoria)

1 Dec 2022 - To date Indexer (Intern) HR Registry Intern

- •Render an effective filling and record management services in HR Registry
- ·Assist with request for personal information in the HR Registry
- •Handle incoming and outgoing correspondence in HR Registry
- •Process documents for archiving and disposal in HR Registry
- •Work with clients and stakeholders on HR Information enquires
- Ensure compliance management practices
- •Create new files for newly appointed employees.
- •Work with persal system (Verifying employee information with persal system as needed when performing certain task)

Leave Administration

- Assist with receiving and capturing leave on persal
- ·Assist with recording leave forms in leave register
- ·Assist in opening and filling temporary incapacity leave file
- •Assisting employees to identify those who qualify for long term service recognition
- ·Assisting employees with leave audits

Recruitment and Selection (2nd Cohort Digitization)

- ·Assist in creating a list of all short listed candidates and capturing
- •Coordinating arrangement for short listed and interview process (Finding out if candidates got interviewed and informing them on interview dates)
- Verifying that selected candidates qualify for short list
- ·Sorting out all necessary documents to be filled into successful candidate's files
- •Issue offer letters and acceptance certificates to successful candidates
- ·Sorting out all files of appointmented candidates Alphabetically

Indexer (BVR- Digitization Hub)

- •Electronically identifying and classifying documents
- •Capturing Birth certificates, IDs, Marriage certificates, Death ceriificates
- •Ensure user only see information they need
- ·Indexing data for ease of search and retrieval
- Validating data

Desktop Technician (IT Intern)

- ·Manage help desk calls on latitude as per SLA.
- •Provide 2nd line support to IT Technicians in the provinces.
- •Configuration of Softwares and Persal System.
- •Travel to provinces when required and support roll out of new projects.
- •Resolve issues for end-users of various form of technology.
- •1st line support for Quality Assurance and Pre Prod Laboratory.
- •Testing of pilot software and devices.
- •2nd line support to all DHA ICT projects.
- •1st line support for the ministry office.
- •Documentation of procedures and process after successfully solving issue at hand.

SPLS Consultants (Centurion)

Oct 2020 - Aug 2021

IT Technician/ End User Training

- •Installation of MTN multimedia computer labs in schools in different provinces, software, configurations, ICT equipment delivery and pickup.
- •Support Replacement of malfunctioning of ICT equipment. Sokware Updates, anti-virus Updates and remote access assistance.
- Trained Teachers in different provinces how to use the multimedia computer lab equipment Installed in schools (End User training)

Phumze Developments

Jan 2019 - March 2019

Intern (Assistance Supervisor)

Monitoring the Installation of fibre:

- Excavation of trenches
- ·Installation of Duct and fiber
- Rehabilitation



Education

Richfield (Durban)

2018

Bachelor Of Science In Information Technology Specialized in Software Development

Esther Payne Smith Secondary (Pietermaritzburg)

2015

Matric

Home Affairs

Dec 2022 - Feb 2023

Completion Of Digitization Training

•Trained in Civic Services, immigration services and Records management

Pretoria college

2021

A+ Certificate

Skills

Communication Skills, Supervision, Productivity Planning, Record Management, Financial Management Microsoft Word. Microsoft Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint, Microsoft Access

Reference

Pearl Myoshe - Home Affairs

Supervisor (HR Registry)

+27 73 095 3585

Lydia Kobo - Home Affairs

Mentor (HR Registry)

+27 65 826 8553

Hulisani Muthaphuli - Home Affairs (IT Manager)

Manager

+27 66 588 3646 / 012 406 7284

Blessing Dube - SPLS Consultants

Manager

+27120234949

Muzi Khumalo - Phumze Developments

CEO

061 041 4317